[{"id": "5fb0875acf631c2414a13b56", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", what are the three names of Daenerys\u2019 dragons?", "answer": "Drogon, Viserion, and Rhaegal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c80c", "question": "What was first made by suspending paraffin in a solution of water and antifreeze?", "answer": "The lava lamp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c957", "question": "Approximately how many miles is an Astronomical Unit?", "answer": "93 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a956", "question": "Which European country replaced the Deutsche mark with the Euro?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffbf91cf6db9ac4808cfa", "question": "As of 2020, which US state had the most craft breweries?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3f", "question": "How many squares are on a checker board?", "answer": "64", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd9691d23c87fd04dd15e06", "question": "Christopher Jones was the captain of what famous ship?", "answer": "The Mayflower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e93a970d6f11f394a3b2d5c", "question": "What does the acronym TAG stand for in the TAG Heuer brand?", "answer": "Techniques d'Avant Garde", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3c", "question": "What animal is depicted on the flag of Wyoming?", "answer": "Buffalo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b993", "question": "What number was retired by the Chicago Bulls to honor Michael Jordan?", "answer": "23", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e9", "question": "What popular spirit can be made from potatoes?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ffa573a3a814d89068c5a", "question": "Which film star's biography is called \"Neither Shaken Nor Stirred\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df9", "question": "Gene Hackman's \"French Connection\" cop is nicknamed for what cartoon character?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd7367e83c707845b2172", "question": "Which NFL team's name was inspired by a famous writer?", "answer": "Baltimore Ravens (The name comes from the poem \"The Raven,\" written by Edgar Allan Poe who called Baltimore home.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901a", "question": "Who painted the \"Rockeby Venus\"?", "answer": "Diego Velazquez", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54c", "question": "\"Consumption\" was the former name of what disease?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa41fbc73aa70ea0b70b12", "question": "Which port city was the first capital of Pakistan?", "answer": "Karachi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9acaebfabb9c85d8a97f", "question": "Stilton cheese originates from which country?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e5", "question": "Who directed the film \"Serpico\"?", "answer": "Sidney Lumet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe528ec1bf59ab7d2e380ff", "question": "What classic school pet is considered a delicacy in Peru?", "answer": "Guinea pig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb3f765ff7d326b622a82", "question": "Where was Budweiser first brewed in the US?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa94a73838c5c8a417f43", "question": "What can\u2019t a cheetah do that a tiger and a puma can do?", "answer": "Retract its claws", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2b", "question": "What Internet portal was sued for copyright infringement in 2000 by the star of \"Young Einstein\"?", "answer": "Yahoo!", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef92086ce05a3942286e7f", "question": "In what state did Bob Dillon grow up?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0f", "question": "Which peninsula is Greece located on?", "answer": "Balkan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e22", "question": "What city's orchestra did Eugene Ormandy conduct for forty-four years?", "answer": "Philadelphia's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e8c2fe83fe1f2a824bde", "question": "Which prominent Kurd, born in Tikrit, united Muslim forces against the crusaders in the 12th century?", "answer": "Saladin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a58", "question": "What literary character comes from Villa Villekulla in Sweden?", "answer": "Pippi Longstocking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078b410eee65b76b9f2665", "question": "Which world leader, who came to power in 1949, is famous for his \"Little Red Book\"?", "answer": "Mao Zedong, or Mao Tse-tung.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf2", "question": "Who created the game Space Invaders?", "answer": "Tomohiro Nishikado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76d", "question": "Who created the icy treat better known as \"popsicle\"?", "answer": "Frank Epperson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b366", "question": "What nationality was the explorer Vitus Bering?", "answer": "Danish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb4", "question": "What did Longfellow say \"must fall...into each life\"?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a1", "question": "What year was fashion designer Gianni Versace killed?", "answer": "1997", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2dc", "question": "What do ladybugs feed on during hibernation?", "answer": "Stored fat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133987f", "question": "In Star Wars, what is the name of Han Solo's ship?", "answer": "The Millenium Falcon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08b", "question": "Which two teams automatically qualified for the 1998 soccer World Cup?", "answer": "France and Brazil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec26ac8dc25ca9e12ef64e", "question": "What is a male goose called?", "answer": "Gander", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c28", "question": "Who wrote \"Little House in the Big Woods\"?", "answer": "Laura Ingalls Wilder", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab4a", "question": "What countries share a land border with Somalia?", "answer": "Ethiopia, Djibouti and Kenya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab4f", "question": "What city is the Lighthouse of Alexandria located in?", "answer": "Pharos", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ec2b15043630d44e5be228d", "question": "Who started the vision for the long-established fashion for the Kentucky Derby races?", "answer": "Col. Meriwether Lewis Clark Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad1", "question": "What do nephologists study?", "answer": "Clouds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f8", "question": "Which state is home to the Fort Apache Indian Reservation?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b32345bbf195a31e15d73a5", "question": "What band released the song \"Mama Weer All Crazee Now\"?", "answer": "Slade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d8242596a59cbdfbd3bf", "question": "According to legend, Napoleon\u2019s troops disfigured which ancient wonder?", "answer": "The Sphinx", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049988cf93664eb1048691", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9b43ebfabb9c85d8a983", "question": "What Norse explorer introduced Christianity to Greenland around 1000 A.D.?", "answer": "Leif Erikson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338926", "question": "Who is the father of the Hulkling?", "answer": "Captain Marvel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d47088f8e329de4f877892", "question": "What is a Winter Banana?", "answer": "A variety of apple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99e", "question": "What well known drug comes from the cinchona tree?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f9", "question": "What was the name of the second orbiter of NASA's space shuttle program?", "answer": "Challenger", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a2", "question": "Who authored 1883's \"The Adventures of Pinocchio\"?", "answer": "Carlo Collodi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc89", "question": "What NHL team's theme music is Aram Khachaturian's most famous composition?", "answer": "The Buffalo Sabres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a510", "question": "Which two independent states exist within Italy's borders?", "answer": "Vatican City and San Marino", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcba", "question": "What model was married to musician Seal?", "answer": "Heidi Klum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc9", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Archie Goodwin?", "answer": "Nero Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d4702ff8e329de4f87788f", "question": "In electronics, what does the word modem stand for?", "answer": "Modulator-demodulator", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b6", "question": "Which movie popularized the phrase \"You had me at hello.\"?", "answer": "Jerry Maguire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ef", "question": "Who played Daniel LaRusso in the 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Ralph Macchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b030", "question": "Before becoming Vice-\u00adPresident, Joe Biden represented what state in the US Senate?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac50", "question": "The earliest evidence of the wheelbarrow was found in which country?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a072", "question": "What planet did Alf come from?", "answer": "Melmac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f164ce1f9b80650dbe7f930", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Robinson Crusoe\"?", "answer": "Daniel Defoe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb3", "question": "Robert Plant was the lead singer for what rock band from 1968 to 1980?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c821877e98cb977789de", "question": "Where was shoe manufacturer Reebok founded?", "answer": "Bolton, England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b064", "question": "The \"CSS Hunley\" was the first of what type of vessel to sink an enemy ship?", "answer": "Submarine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afbf", "question": "Who was the first British monarch to live in Buckingham Palace?", "answer": "Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e3", "question": "What was the first name of Martin Short's character on his TV show \"Primetime Glick\"?", "answer": "Jiminy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9b", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"And Outcast of the Islands\"?", "answer": "Joseph Conrad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa566cc73aa70ea0b70b2b", "question": "Which country hosts the World Ice Golf Championship?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b55", "question": "Which ear did artist Vincent Van Gogh cut off?", "answer": "Left", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d4", "question": "What part of the eye is damaged by glaucoma?", "answer": "The optic nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76e", "question": "\"Old Scratch\" is a nickname for whom?", "answer": "Satan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339645", "question": "Where did Kevin's parents go for Christmas in the 1990 movie \"Home Alone\"?", "answer": "France", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c7", "question": "What object marks the ceremonial location of the South Pole?", "answer": "A red and white striped pole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e94357ccba3ffe45786d0", "question": "What element is assigned the chemical symbol Cf?", "answer": "Californium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c5dafbde8045e48466b1", "question": "An \"unkindness\" refers to a group of what animal?", "answer": "Ravens -- They have a bad reputation, and have been considered bad omens for centuries.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ec7240f57c9fcac0ce7197d", "question": "What was the pennant number of HMS Hood?", "answer": "51", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909caddbb53d1af658864d3", "question": "What ABC Original Movie, starring Jenny McCarthy, air on December 10, 2006?", "answer": "Santa Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea9", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"The Harder They Fall\"?", "answer": "Humphrey Bogart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4301ff048f679a45ab7f", "question": "What is a hominid?", "answer": "An Upright-Walking Primate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76bb2eec85e375820b2c7", "question": "Where can you golf the world\u2019s highest elevation championship course?", "answer": "La Paz Golf Club, Bolivia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc3edec223966ae8f8882", "question": "Which player graced the cover of the videogame \"Madden NFL 17\"?", "answer": "Rob Gronkowski", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d00", "question": "In which movie did Angela Lansbury portray a witch?", "answer": "Bedknobs and Broomsticks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339410", "question": "What was the maiden name of \"Leave It to Beaver\" TV mom June Cleaver?", "answer": "Bronson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe938a76bd93ce3a4e5f687", "question": "What is the standard unit of kinetic energy?", "answer": "Joule", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d0062596a59cbdfbd376", "question": "Who said, \"Call no man unhappy until he is married\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeff", "question": "What city hosted the Summer Olympics in 1996?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a3", "question": "The annual Miss America Pageant is held in what city?", "answer": "Atlantic City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe000661cf6db9ac4808d11", "question": "When was Hong Kong transferred from Britain to China?", "answer": "1997", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fa", "question": "In the movie \"The Big Lebowski\", what item did the Dude take from the Big Lebowski mansion as compensation?", "answer": "A rug", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e51", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Mitchell\"?", "answer": "Merlin Olsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df7", "question": "What is the subject of Claude Lanzmann's award-winning nine-hour film \"Shoah\"?", "answer": "The Holocaust", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97d", "question": "What nuts are used to make a Satay sauce?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d2", "question": "What comic sang in public for the first time at her Broadway debut as Rizzo in Grease?", "answer": "Rosie O'Donnell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a109", "question": "Who does Fred Savage play on the TV show \"The Wonder Years\"?", "answer": "Kevin Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad3", "question": "What was the original name of Fyodor Dostoevsky's \"Crime and Punishment\"?", "answer": "The Drunkards", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede1cb6ce05a3942286dc5", "question": "In a Thanksgiving episode on TV's \"Friends\", what dish did Monica have to make for Ross?", "answer": "Lumpy mashed potatoes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87b", "question": "Sinologists study which country?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fed2ba2ec223966ae8f890f", "question": "On what avenue does the traditional New York City Easter Parade and Bonnet Festival take place?", "answer": "Fifth Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ef", "question": "Of the six main cast members on the TV show \u201cFriends\u201d, which was the oldest?", "answer": "Lisa Kudrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd6f", "question": "What thin cotton fabric used in summer suits takes its name from Persian words for \"milk and sugar\"?", "answer": "Seersucker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017378544491cbd7c5a178b", "question": "How did the U.S. state Tennessee aquire the nickname, \"The Volunteer State\"?", "answer": "It became known as \"The Volunteer State\" during the War of 1812 due to its prominent role of sending 1,500 volunteer soldiers.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339774", "question": "Which company created the Oscar-winning film Finding Nemo?", "answer": "Pixar Animation Studios", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b838", "question": "What 1960s invention was originally called the \"Pleasure Pit\"?", "answer": "Waterbed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a0", "question": "What is the oldest marathon race in the US?", "answer": "Boston Marathon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c779", "question": "What aquatic reptile can hold its breath under water for up to 15 minutes?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c81", "question": "What famous American author published Ulysses S. Grant's \"Personal Memoirs\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a761", "question": "In which US city will you find Louis Armstrong International Airport?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28f", "question": "What was Cat Stevens' birth name?", "answer": "Steven Demetre Georgiou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a98", "question": "What early rock and roll pioneer's real first and middle name was Charles Hardin?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65e151f3c0ead6880d626", "question": "In Jesus' parable from the Bible, on what did the foolish man build his house?", "answer": "Sand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f3f7caf848b908361b86c", "question": "What do the numbers on a roulette wheel add up to?", "answer": "666", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9bb", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Capricorn\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "The goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a81f", "question": "On which South Pacific island could you sail into Papeete Bay?", "answer": "Tahiti", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f4", "question": "What is considered as the first daily comic strip in the US?", "answer": "Mutt and Jeff", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d1", "question": "What is the function of the Thyroid Gland?", "answer": "To regulate growth and metabolism\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1e", "question": "If cattle are bovine, what are sheep?", "answer": "Ovine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3f", "question": "In Italian, the Mona Lisa is called what?", "answer": "La Giocondo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4b38f06d333868d34d6d9", "question": "Which song produced a Christmas truce during World War I?", "answer": "\"Silent Night\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b56801dd7bf43be5e7d0", "question": "What does \"dachshund\" mean?", "answer": "Badger dog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae9431574a5ce6b56b8244", "question": "What job did Agatha Christie's second husband do?", "answer": "Archaeologist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a8", "question": "What was the name of Alexander the Great's famous horse?", "answer": "Bucephalas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d12", "question": "Whose last novel was 1961's \"The Winter of Our Discontent\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd78", "question": "What was the home country of famed jeweller Peter Carl Faberge?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bb", "question": "What is measured in Amperes?", "answer": "Electric current", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02a", "question": "How is Edson Arantes do Nascimento better known?", "answer": "Pele\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21d", "question": "What city was Martin Luther King, Jr. killed in?", "answer": "Memphis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe12dd1e39efa6330e0fecf", "question": "In which US state is the largest county?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b22501dd7bf43be5e79a", "question": "Talking to people who agree with you is like doing what?", "answer": "Preaching to the choir", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc43", "question": "What famous tennis player became Novak Djokovic's coach in 2013?", "answer": "Boris Becker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca8", "question": "Who kicked last-second field goals to win two different Super Bowls?", "answer": "Adam Vinateri", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc1c76ce05a3942286f15", "question": "What was Luke Skywalker's original name?", "answer": "Like Starkiller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c8f2fbde8045e48466e4", "question": "Which farm animal is known as a ram, ewe, and lamb?", "answer": "Sheep -- Female sheep are called ewes, male sheep are called rams, and baby sheep are called lambs.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b1d", "question": "Who played Gilligan on \"Gilligan's Island\"?", "answer": "Bob Denver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398db", "question": "On what TV show did Amanda Blake play the role of saloon/brothel manager Miss Kitty Russell?", "answer": "Gunsmoke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c93", "question": "How does Juliet die in Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "She stabs herself", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad57", "question": "Queen Mary of England made her reputation by trying to rid her country of what segment of the population?", "answer": "Protestants", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb7", "question": "What was Malawi formerly known as?", "answer": "Nyasaland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339489", "question": "Who played the warden in the movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173abe44491cbd7c5a179b", "question": "What is the birth name of African-American abolitionist Harriet Tubman?", "answer": "Araminta Ross -- She was born into slavery.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb86", "question": "What South African golfer is nicknamed \"The Big Easy\"?", "answer": "Ernie Els", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa08", "question": "Budapest is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c48e877e98cb977789a0", "question": "Where are the \"Seven Colored Earths\"?", "answer": "Mauritius", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600242794be4723ccac22186", "question": "Atticus Finch is the name of the narrator\u2019s father in which classic 1960 novel?", "answer": "\"To Kill a Mockingbird\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339474", "question": "In what city does the movie \"Mrs. Doubtfire\" take place?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339830", "question": "What movie, directed by the Coen brothers, won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\" in 2008?", "answer": "No Country for Old Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d07e91a1c922dd1ac64bd", "question": "Which Science Fiction author wrote \"The Day of the Triffids\"?", "answer": "John Wyndham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c171", "question": "What is the alternative name of scallions?", "answer": "Spring onions or green onions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a78e", "question": "What is the capital of Libya?", "answer": "Tripoli", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc5", "question": "What is the last name of John, Michael, and Wendy in \"Peter Pan\"?", "answer": "Darling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a7486c0f9723ab15cb5d", "question": "What was the first toy advertised on television?", "answer": "Mr. Potato Head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b33", "question": "What 1980s movie soundtrack gave us the #1 hit by the band Berlin titled \"Take My Breath Away\"?", "answer": "Top Gun", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18a", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Nine Tonight\"?", "answer": "Bob Seger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a9ec20565ad31a57c80d", "question": "The Nazi organization NSDAP stands for what?", "answer": "National German Workers' Party (Nationalsozialistische Deutsche Arbeiterparteiz)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3c6eff048f679a45ab3d", "question": "Catagelophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Being ridiculed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8d73ec223966ae8f8854", "question": "The PlayStation prototype was designed by Sony in collaboration with which company?", "answer": "Nintendo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b778", "question": "The traditional chef's hat has 100 pleats, which symbolizes the number of what?", "answer": "Ways to cook an egg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339336", "question": "What was the title of the TV series \"M*A*S*H\" theme song?", "answer": "Suicide is Painless", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7bfe0877e98cb9777896b", "question": "What country borders the Caspian Sea, Persian Gulf, and Gulf of Oman?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6550fae7e414034b5aeae", "question": "Until 1792, Kentucky was part of which state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99b8221a8909e5c332d2c", "question": "When was the film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\" released?", "answer": "1988", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2af", "question": "What nation was led by Casimir the Great?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339deb", "question": "What was the name of Willie Tyler's dummy?", "answer": "Lester", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946f", "question": "What was Toula's wedding present from her parents in the movie \"My Big Fat Greek Wedding\"?", "answer": "A house", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8f", "question": "What is the capital of Dominica?", "answer": "Roseau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9de", "question": "Bubble Wrap was invented while researchers were trying to make what?", "answer": "Wallpaper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af77", "question": "What collapsed in 1928 near the city of Santa Paula, killing over 450 people?", "answer": "St. Francis Dam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a60d", "question": "Which country has the world's largest protected nature reserve?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523e1d736d4be723796b4b", "question": "In which Canadian city would you find the largest mall in North America?", "answer": "Edmonton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b612", "question": "In baseball, which number references the shortstop?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73405eec85e375820b22b", "question": "How old was the youngest American serviceman in World War II?", "answer": "12", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a12f", "question": "At what address did the TV's \"Addams Family\" live?", "answer": "0001 Cemetery Lane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0da", "question": "In 1995, who became the first Republican Speaker of the House in 40 years?", "answer": "Newt Gingrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6018bc40d96d05b23b281655", "question": "What documents were responsible for establishing the 17th Parallel as the line that separated Vietnam during the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Geneva Accords", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cb7dbb53d1af658864d8", "question": "What band released a single in 1977 entitled \"Father Christmas\"?", "answer": "The Kinks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "593c4b58b8198b9a2b077962", "question": "The film \"Casablanca\" takes place during which global conflict?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b6", "question": "What process includes the following phases: prophase, metaphase, anaphase, and telophase?", "answer": "Cell mitosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a487", "question": "In which ocean is the area known as Polynesia located?", "answer": "Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4bef49076251badbeaca", "question": "Which U.S. President had his sister initially serve as First Lady?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland -- \u00a0His sister Rose Cleveland took on the duties of First Lady until he married his bride Frances in June 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e39", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"The Old Sea-dog at the Admiral Benbow\"?", "answer": "Treasure Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76e", "question": "The Gaza Strip extends northeast from what peninsula?", "answer": "Sinai Peninsula", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd5", "question": "By what collective name are Medusa, Stheno and Euryale usually known?", "answer": "Gorgons", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a162a64f01ec323f8491723", "question": "What carries sensations from the tongue to the brain?", "answer": "Lingual nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6002413e4be4723ccac22173", "question": "Sydney Carton is the central character in what Charles Dickens novel?", "answer": "\"A Tale of Two Cities\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a25f1016682715b82711cdb", "question": "What did \"My Favorite Martian\" have to do before he could become invisible in the 1960s TV show by the same name?", "answer": "Raise his antennae", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f1b", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both John Gavin and Rex Harrison?", "answer": "Julius Caesar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523f9b736d4be723796b59", "question": "What distiller and entrepreneur founded the town of Walkerville, which is now a heritage neighborhood of Windsor, Ontario in Canada?", "answer": "Hiram Walker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b6b1e662d71a5365100c", "question": "What is the name of the vampire hunter and animator in Laurell K. Hamilton's \"The Harlequin\"?", "answer": "Anita Blake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ef", "question": "Who was appointed the first leader of the Tuskegee Institute in 1881?", "answer": "Booker T. Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b99", "question": "In 2000, who became the first Asian woman to host \"Saturday Night Live\"?", "answer": "Lucy Liu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c6cb877e98cb977789c0", "question": "The Great Pyramid of Cholula is located in what country?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b30b", "question": "Who uttered the line \"There you go again\" during a debate?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc6d76de0eb824d4052f9", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest living tree canopy, the size of three soccer fields?", "answer": "India -- A 550-year-old ficus benghalensis tree there, known as Thimmamma Marrimanu, has combined crowns that span 5.41 acres.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133916e", "question": "What the are the first names of \"The Brothers Coen\"?", "answer": "Joel and Ethan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601370411381754895396380", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", what is the name of the pizza delivery?", "answer": "Little Nero's Pizza -- It is a parody of Little Ceasar's Pizza.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ad8c01dd7bf43be5e77a", "question": "Where does the color sepia come from?", "answer": "The ink of cuttlefish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa3f86ce05a3942286eae", "question": "What song does Tom Cruise lip-sync to in his underwear in \"Risky Business\"?", "answer": "\"Old Time Rock & Roll\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339270", "question": "What is the name of the Alicia Keys backup singer who won season 2 of The Voice?", "answer": "Jermaine Paul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af31", "question": "What organisation was given the only Nobel peace prize awarded during World War I?", "answer": "International Red Cross", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad9", "question": "In 1997, what country singer formed the band, The Ranch, with two fellow Australian musicians?", "answer": "Keith Urban", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe377bb0ada16518afdc04b", "question": "After giving up mural painting, Gustav Klimt designed for what industry?", "answer": "Fashion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e9", "question": "Which four US states share a border with Mexico?", "answer": "Arizona, California, New Mexico and Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3c1ee4f032c0db195b47b", "question": "How many passengers were aboard the Mayflower when it set sail for the New World in 1620?", "answer": "There were 102 passengers aboard the Mayflower, and the crew is estimated to have been about 30.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cd40e06685cf15b733e9896", "question": "In fencing what is the name of the action when two fencers make physical contact with any part of their bodies (or hilts)?", "answer": "Corps-a-corps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339984", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Barney's snowplowing business?", "answer": "Plow King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a07b", "question": "Which British comedian became well known for his broken microphone routine?", "answer": "Norman Collier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984b", "question": "The music duo \"Daft Punk\" consists of which two French musicians?", "answer": "Thomas Bangalter and Guy-Manuel de Homem-Christo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2d", "question": "What movie was partially inspired by Jean Shepherd's unpublished story \"Flick's Tongue\"?", "answer": "A Christmas Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bc89fb6c85e9e634ff5d", "question": "Majorca belongs to which island group?", "answer": "Balearic Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fb086e4cf631c2414a13b55", "question": "In the TV show \"Friends\", what was the name of Ross and Monica\u2019s dog when they were kids?", "answer": "Chi Chi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed7", "question": "What kind of animal's kidnapping is solved in \"Ace Ventura: Pet Detective\"?", "answer": "A dolphin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e9a606d333868d34d757", "question": "During World War II, the U.S. purchase more than 150 million pounds of what to feed its troops?", "answer": "SPAM", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f01", "question": "What author created the character of Miss Marple?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4c", "question": "Who wrote the \"Man in the Iron Mask\"?", "answer": "Alexandre Dumas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be71", "question": "What is the Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum also known as?", "answer": "The Grand Old Lady", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ab", "question": "Which country does paella come from?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121bc863c99d48cd169b10", "question": "When someone is breviloquent, they use very few what?", "answer": "Words -- Eloquent people speak beautifully and often at length, whereas breviloquent people like to keep it brief.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ae", "question": "Who was the first African-American to win an Academy Award for an acting role?", "answer": "Hattie McDaniel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25ee9e6682715b82711cce", "question": "Which European republic was the first to reach Australia in 1606?", "answer": "The Dutch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d4", "question": "Under what brand name does Roche market the sedative diazepam?", "answer": "Valium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909cbd7bb53d1af658864dc", "question": "What holiday is celebrated on December 26th in Canada?", "answer": "Boxing Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba13", "question": "What position did football hall-of-famer Dick Butkus play with the Chicago Bears?", "answer": "Linebacker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0e", "question": "What type of two-sailed vessel is particularly adept at sailing upwind?", "answer": "Sloop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b146", "question": "In what year was Stanley sent to Africa to search for Livingstone?", "answer": "1871", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9b", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Rights of Man\"?", "answer": "Thomas Paine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6d", "question": "Liege municipality is located in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ebf", "question": "Whose girlfriends are named Callie Shaw and Iola Morton?", "answer": "The Hardy Boys", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911d", "question": "What year did E. M. Forster publish the novel \"Howards End\"?", "answer": "1910", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab9b", "question": "The port of Piraeus is located in which European country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3a", "question": "What poker hand are you holding if you have \"two fish-hooks\"?", "answer": "A pair of jacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b930", "question": "What is the official score of a forfeited major league baseball game?", "answer": "9-0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a59", "question": "What character from \"The Beverly Hillbillies\" had the same name as Moses' father-in-law in the Bible?", "answer": "Jethro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9e", "question": "In a circus, a funambulist is a what?", "answer": "Tightrope walker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d82", "question": "What signature tune of Glenn Miller's orchestra was originally called \"Now I Lay Me Down to Weep\"?", "answer": "Moonlight Serenade", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b401", "question": "Which was the first US city to host the Summer Olympic Games?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c311", "question": "What element are diamonds made of?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b836", "question": "What is the diameter of a basketball hoop?", "answer": "18 inches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b978", "question": "What is the name of the cup used by Christ at the last supper?", "answer": "The Holy Grail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7147a9e54d890926f6dd", "question": "The second highest mountain on land is K2.  What does the letter \"K\" stand for?", "answer": "Karakoram -- K2 is located in the Karakoram Mountain Range.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b06be662d71a53650fc8", "question": "The four routes through the Vatican Museums all end at what showstopper?", "answer": "Michelangelo\u2019s Creation of Adam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef66be6ce05a3942286e7c", "question": "Which actor received Emmy nominations for playing the same character on three shows?", "answer": "Kelsey Grammer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ab", "question": "Who played Lofty in the TV series \"Eastenders\"?", "answer": "Tom Watt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbedf003d27d341092bd2", "question": "Where is the world's largest tropical orchid garden?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c308", "question": "How long is the giraffe's tongue?", "answer": "17 inches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c47", "question": "What ventriloquist was best known for his dummy Charlie McCarthy?", "answer": "Edgar Bergen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2b", "question": "Who became an animated Disney megastar after replacing Oswald the Lucky Rabbit?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c35e", "question": "What is the dog breed \"Borzoi\" sometimes called?", "answer": "Russian wolfhound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ac", "question": "The dish \"rosti\" originated from which country?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f0b4fe83fe1f2a824c12", "question": "At the Seder table, people eat and drink in a reclining position. What does this represent?", "answer": "Freedom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d2", "question": "How many claws does a domestic cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60078566bd51d85e222ab65e", "question": "Who said: \"I\u2019m the president of the United States, and I\u2019m not going to eat any more broccoli\"?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush (He once made a joke that the workers in the Office of Personnel Management would get merit pay \"in broccoli\").", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea5", "question": "What TV series about International Rescue pilots was filmed in \"supermarionation\"?", "answer": "Thunderbirds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e0a", "question": "What 1984 hit repeats the phrase \"Come on, shine your heavenly body tonight\"?", "answer": "Lucky Star", "category": "entertainment"}]